theitjobboard.co.uk 2017-06-06

# PP and Cookies Policy

**Effective Date: January 13th, 2017**

This Privacy Policy for Dice Careers Limited describes our practices on the collection, use and disclosure of your information in connection with our parent entity, DHI Group, Inc., and subsidiaries and affiliates acting on our behalf (collectively, "DHI"). When used herein, the terms "Dice," "we," "us," and "our" refer to DHI. Other than the requirements to which we adhere under the Privacy Shield framework and its accountability for onward transfer of personal information principal, we cannot, and do not, assume responsibility for the privacy or information policies, practices or actions of any third parties. We at DHI are committed to good privacy practices regarding your personally identifiable information. Your loyalty as a customer or visitor is important, and we hope that our concerns regarding your privacy, as described in this policy (the "Privacy Policy" or "Policy"), demonstrate our commitment to making your experience with DHI an enjoyable and satisfying one. 

DHI and its subsidiaries, such as UK.dice.com and SAP.dice.com participate in and have certified their compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. DHI is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. [[https://www.privacyshield.gov/list]](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). 

DHI is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. DHI complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, DHI is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, DHI may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

[

](http://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/validation?rid=e0619609-2aa7-413a-88b2-20553e8fbc6b)

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [ [https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint]](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

DHI complies with the the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from Switzerland. DHI has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view DHI’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>. 

This Privacy Policy governs your interaction with the Sites and your registration for and use of our online services (collectively, the "Services"). Except as set forth within this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use Agreement and other published guidelines, we do not release personally identifiable information about our users and visitors without their permission. This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by the Sites and mobile applications that link to this privacy policy. Accordingly, we encourage you to review the entire Privacy Policy. Please click on any of the links below to review that particular section. 

  1. The information we gather
  2. How we use the information we gather
  3. How we share information we gather
  4. Tracking Technologies
  5. Security
  6. Survey & Sweepstakes
  7. Social Media Features
  8. Facebook Connect
  9. Choice and Correction of personally Identifiable Information
  10. Changes to this Privacy Policy
  11. Questions? 

## A. The information we gather

We gather two (2) types of information about users: 

**1\. Non-personally identifiable information (information that does not identify a specific individual):** When visitors use the Services, we collect and aggregate information indicating, among other things, which pages were visited, the order in which they were visited, and which links were "clicked." Collecting such information involves the collection and logging of IP addresses, operating system, and browser software used by each user of the Services. Although such information is not personally identifiable, we can determine from the IP address a visitor’s Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. The non-personally identifiable information we collect helps us identify the most popular areas of the Sites and determine the effectiveness of our promotional activities. In addition, we may disclose some of this information to advertisers to inform them of the number of people who have seen and/or clicked through their advertisements. We collect non-personally identifiable information in part through the use of "cookies." For more information, read the information under "Cookies" in section D below. 

On mobile applications, we use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Services on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregate usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit. 

On mobile applications, we may send push notifications to your device. You may opt-out of these at the device level. 

**2\. Personally identifiable information:** In certain areas of the Sites, such as those in which you complete a profile, submit your resume, create a new account, or enter DHI-sponsored contests or promotions, we may request that you provide us with certain personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, zip code, mobile number, profession, or work experience. We will, in such situations, seek to identify which informational items are required and which are optional. In some instances, we may collect geo-location based information for the purpose of helping identify jobs in your area. We may share this information for the sole purpose of providing you this feature. You may opt-out of location based services by editing the setting at the device level. If you post profiles and resumes on our Sites, such information can be viewed by our customers. At any time, job seekers may elect that their profile and resume not be searchable by our customers by logging into their account and changing the status of their profile or, if that is not possible, they may contact us at [uksupport@dice.com](mailto:uksupport@dice.com) and we will make the change for them. 

In addition, job seekers may elect to make their profile searchable by our customers on a confidential basis only. In this case, the user's name and contact information will not be displayed to customers performing searches on the Site. If the customer desires to contact the confidential job seeker regarding an employment opportunity, they will send an email to the job seeker through our system. We will forward the email to the seeker's email address. The seeker's email address will not be provided directly to the customer. When posting a resume confidentially, it is the job seeker's responsibility to ensure that their contact information is not included within their resume attachment. 

_DHI Services are not available to children under 13 years of age._ We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. 

Please note that we cannot control the acts of users of the Services. All members and visitors should be aware that, when they disclose personally identifiable information in a resume or profile or other medium, the information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited email from other parties outside DHI. In the event that you encounter any DHI user who is improperly collecting or using information about you or other users, please contact [uksupport@dice.com](mailto:uksupport@dice.com) . 

## B. How we use the information we gather

Please take some time to familiarize yourself with the different ways we use the information we gather. DHI encourages all third parties involved, including but not limited to its advertisers, to adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our visitors and users and to otherwise handle personally identifiable information in a responsible manner,. Nevertheless, in the event you encounter any third party associated with, or who claims association with, DHI who you feel is improperly collecting or using information about you, please contact [uksupport@dice.com](mailto:uksupport@dice.com)

**1\. How we use non-personally identifiable information:** We use non-personally identifiable information in aggregate form to build higher quality, more useful Services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our visitors and users, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the Services. We may provide statistical information based on this data to advertisers, users, and other current and potential business partners. We may also use the aggregate data to inform these third parties as to the number of people who have seen and clicked through links to their sites. 

**2\. How we use personally identifiable information:** We may use the personally identifiable information a user submits for any purposes related to DHI business, including, but not limited: 

  1. To understand a user’s needs and create content that is relevant to the user; 
  2. To generate statistical studies; 
  3. To conduct market research and planning by sending user surveys; 
  4. To notify user referrals of DHI services, information, or products when a user requests that DHI send such information to referrals; 
  5. To improve services, information, and products; 
  6. To help a user complete a transaction, or provide services or customer support to users and to recipients of DHI products; 
  7. To communicate with the user and with recipients of DHI products and services; 
  8. To email users about services, information, products and offers from our business partners (and as set forth in section C, How we share information we gather); 
  9. To personalize the Sites for the user; 
  10. To notify the user of any changes with the Sites which may affect the user; 
  11. To enforce terms of use on the Sites; 
  12. To allow the user to purchase products, access services, or otherwise engage in activities the user selects; and
  13. To allow us to contact you by phone and/or email. In some cases, this includes text messaging of alerts and carrier charges may apply. 

User names, identifications ("IDs"), and email addresses (as well as any additional information that a user may choose to post) may be publicly available on the Sites when a user voluntarily and publicly discloses personally identifiable information, such as when a user uses features to send a message to another user, or as part of a message posted to a public forum or a publicly-released software application. Users may not be able to change or remove public postings once posted. Such personally identifiable information may be used by visitors of these pages to send unsolicited messages. DHI is not responsible for any consequences which may occur from the use of personally identifiable information that a user chooses to submit to public pages. 

With respect to surveys, in the event that responses are publicly disclosed, users will be notified at the time they take the survey. DHI will disclose only aggregate information regarding its users, i.e., anonymous information that does not identify any specific individual. Circumstances under which DHI would publicly disclose such aggregate information include, but are not limited to, sharing survey results with the Sites’ users, providing data to DHI advertisers on user preferences and/or demographics, and publicizing overall usage data in press communications. Where surveys allow users to submit written comments, and where DHI advises users of the possibility of such disclosure at the time they take the survey, DHI reserves the right to disclose any information provided by users, provided that no personally identifiable information identifying a specific user is disclosed. Participation in surveys is at a user’s option; DHI does not conduct mandatory surveys. 

## C. How we share information we gather

Subject to the foregoing, DHI uses your personally identifiable information in several ways. DHI may share your personally identifiable information with service providers to help us with our business activities such as processing credit cards, email and social network marketing, offering customer service, or operating a community forum. These service providers are authorized to use your personally identifiable information only as necessary to provide these services to us. With respect to job applications, DHI will not disclose your profile or resume on our Sites to prospective employers without your consent or to carry out your instructions. 

If you "opt in" to receive promotional materials from third parties, information you have made available to us may be made available to third parties who provide goods or services that we believe may be of interest to you. You may "opt out" of receiving such materials at any time in a variety of ways: by using the "opt-out" link included in each email, by changing your subscriptions preferences on the "user settings" page in your DHI account or by contacting us at [uksupport@dice.com](mailto:uksupport@dice.com). If you have provided more than one email address to our service, you may continue to be contacted, unless you request to unsubscribe each email address you have provided. If you opted in to receive information directly from third parties, then you must contact those third parties directly to opt-out. 

In addition, DHI reserves the right to share aggregate information collected from users of the Sites, without prior notice, with entities that are part of the DHI corporate family and unrelated third parties. Aggregate information is used in a collective manner and no single person can be identified by such compiled information. 

In order to effectively tailor our services, these Sites may sell your personal information to third party consultants and business partners, including, but not limited to other lead generation companies (collectively "Third Party Contractors") to collect, compile, organize, and market to you related services. 

When you submit any personally identifiable information on this Site, we will obtain your consent authorizing the Sites to sell to Third Party Contractors any and all personally identifiable information that is necessary to enable additional service offerings. 

To provide services to our customers, DHI collects indexed content from a variety of publicly available websites. Indexed content may include personal information such as post on blogs. In general, such indexed content is available through standard search engines or by visiting the websites themselves. DHI may append this information to your profile or use this content to create a profile, whether or not an individual has an account with us. If you would like to remove the information we collect, see section I to submit your request. DHI has no ownership rights to the indexed content sourced from third party sites and cannot guarantee that we will not collect information from a publicly available source at a later point in time. 

Please note that DHI reserves the right to disclose information submitted by or concerning any visitor or user as we reasonably feel is necessary to protect our systems or business. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. We cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who may be using our servers or Services for illegal activities. We also reserve the right to report any suspected illegal activity to law enforcement for investigation or prosecution, or to suspend or terminate your use of the Services in connection with any suspected illegal or infringing activity or if you are in violation of our Terms of Use Agreement or other published guidelines. 

If DHI is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on the Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. DHI reserves the right to assign, sell, license, or otherwise transfer to a third party your personally identifiable information in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture, or other transfer or disposition of any portion or all of DHI’s or its affiliated entities’ assets or stock.
